>> 凯尔: 所以，让我们确保我们都在同一个页面上。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So let's just make sure
we're all on the same page here.
我们回顾 JavaScript 不是一种解释语言，
We recall that JavaScript is
not an interpreted language and
这一步是逐步向前迈出的一步
that it goes step by
step one line at a time.
但是，我们应该将 JavaScript 视为两个传递过程。
But rather, we should think about
JavaScript as a two pass processing.
第一次通过，我们可以称之为编译或解析 ( 如果我们感觉更好 ) 。
First pass, we could call it compilation
or parsing if we feel better about that.
但我们要通过整个密码
But we're gonna go
through the entire code.
在解析和编译期间会发生很多事情
And there's lots of things that happen
during the parsing and compilation,
但最主要的事情是范围
but the main thing that
happens is all of the scopes,
所有这些彩色的大理石水桶这些都是被制造的
all of those colored marble buckets,
the plan for those all get created.
我们计算出所有范围的界限。
We figure out where all
the scope boundaries are.
事实上所有的标识符都提到了
And indeed,
all of the identifier references,
这些颜色被编码成弹珠
those are color coded as marbles.
我们会有一个红色的大理石或蓝色的大理石或绿色的大理石。
So we'll have a red marble or
a blue marble or a green marble.
我们会用这个关于大理石颜色的信息
And we'll use that information
about the color of the marble and
它的来源是什么信息是关键的
what bucket it comes from,
that information is critical and
当我们执行代码时，在第二次传递中有用。
useful in the second pass
when we execute code.
所以我们要通过谈话作为我们的评论
So we're gonna run through
the conversation as our review.
我希望你们所有人都能参与
And I'm gonna expect, hope,
that all of you are participating with it,
而不仅仅是我
rather than me only
being the one speaking.
所以跟我一起走吧
So follow along with me as we do this.
如果你在看 livestream，大声说话给你的电脑，
If you're watching on the livestream,
talk out loud to your computer,
即使那感觉太傻了
even if that feels silly.
这也是老师的戏法，如果你用嘴巴说的话，
Again, it's the teacher trick, that if
you physically say this with your mouth,
它会帮助你记住这些东西
it'll help you to remember these things.
所以我们再谈这个话题
So we'll go through this
conversation again,
第一次通过编译，第二次通过执行。
the first pass compilation,
second pass execution.
在编译阶段，请记住它是编译器和作用域管理器或
In the compilation phase, remember it's
the compiler and the scope manager or
解析器，不管你想怎么想，作用域管理器，
the parser, whatever you want to think of,
and the scope manager,
他们会说话的
they're gonna be talking.
所以我们会扮演这个解析器或编译器的角色。
So we'll play the part of that parser or
compiler.
我们会到达第一条线我们会说正如编译器说的
And we'll arrive at something like line
one and we'll say, as compiler will say,
嘿，范围管理器，我们现在在说全局范围。
hey, scope manager,
we're talking to the global scope now.
我们会说，嘿，范围的管理者，
And we'll say, hey, scope manager,
我有一个叫变量的正式声明
I have a formal declaration for
a variable called.
>> 扬声器 2: 教师。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Teacher.
>> 凯尔: 老师，对，你以前听过吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Teacher, right, and
have you ever heard of that before?
所以我们在和红桶说话
So we're talking to the red bucket.
我们会说你以前听过吗
We'll say have you ever
heard of it before?
如果我们见到瓦尔老师几次在同一范围内
If we'd seen var teacher a couple of
times in the same scope, the reason for
问题是我们不需要用同样的名字来制作多个弹珠
that question is we don't need to make
multiple marbles with the same name.
它只需要为同一作用域创建一次，并且
It only needs to be created once for
the same scope, and
根本就没有重新创造的东西，好吗 ?
there really is no such thing
as recreating it, okay?
问题是你有没有听说过这个叫老师的标识符，
So that question would be have you ever
heard of this identifier called teacher,
会有什么反应吗
and the response would be?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。 >> 凯尔: 不，但是我创造了，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: No, but I've created,
什么颜色的大理石
what a color marble?
>> 扬声器 2: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red marble.
>> 凯尔: 红色的大理石， [ SOUND] 我们把它放到红桶里，好吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble, [SOUND] we
drop it in the red bucket, okay?
现在我们找到下一个正式声明，第 3 行。
Now we find the next formal declaration,
line 3.
全球范围我有一份正式声明
Hey global scope,
I have a formal declaration for-
>> 扬声器 2: 其他类。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Other class.
>> 凯尔: 其他类，有听过吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Other class, ever heard of it?
答案是- >> 演讲者 2: 不。
And the answer is-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔: 从未听说过，但
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Never heard of it, but
这里是你的 -- > 众说家 2: 红色。
here's your-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
>> 凯尔: 红色大理石， [SOUND] 我们把它放到红桶里。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble,
[SOUND] we drop it in the red bucket.
顺便说下，全球范围，红色的大理石，指向一个功能。
By the way, global scope, that red marble,
that was pointing at a function.
所以我们需要一个新的水桶，我们需要水桶里的桶。
So we need a new bucket,
we need a bucket inside of a bucket.
你能给我们做个蓝桶吗
Can you make us a blue bucket?
好的，现在让我们谈谈蓝色桶。
Sure, okay now let's talk
about the blue bucket.
于是我们进入了蓝色的桶里，移动到第 4 行
So we stepped inside of the blue bucket,
we move to line 4 and
我们再找一份正式声明
we find another formal declaration.
嘿，其他课的范围。
Hey, scope of other class.
嘿蓝桶镜我给老师正式声明了
Hey, blue bucket scope,
I've a formal declaration for teacher.
你有听过吗 答案是吗 ?
Have you ever heard it?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。 >> 凯尔: 为什么，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Why,
我们为什么不听老师的
why haven't we heard of teacher?
>演讲者 3: 这是一个新的水桶。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: It's a new bucket.
>> 凯尔: 我们在这里跟一个不同的水桶说话，对。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Cuz we're talking to
a different bucket here, right.
重要的是牢记这一点因为当我们进行处理的时候
And it's important to keep that in mind
because when we get to processing,
我们会问其他的范围
we will ask other scopes.
但我们只是在考虑这是正式声明
But here we're only considering,
since it's a formal declaration,
我们只是要求它是为了这个特定的范围而创建的吗
we're only asking has it been created for
this particular scope?
答案是不，但你的颜色是大理石吗 ?
And the answer is no, but
here's your what color marble?
>> 演讲者 2: 蓝色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Blue.
>> 凯尔: 蓝色大理石，好， [SOUND] 现在它在蓝色的桶里。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Blue marble, okay,
[SOUND] now it's in the blue bucket.
我们在那个功能上看不到任何正式的声明
We don't see any more formal
declarations in that function, so
我们又回到了全球范围的红桶里
we step back out to the global scope,
the red bucket.
我们发现的下一个正式声明是在第 8 行。
The next formal declaration
we find is on line 8.
全局范围，我有一个叫标识的正式声明吗 ?
Hey, global scope, I have a formal
declaration for an identifier called?
>> 扬声器 2: 询问。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Ask.
>> 凯尔: 问，听说过吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Ask, ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔: 但这里是您的 - > > 扬声器 2: 红色。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: But here's your-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
>> 凯尔: 红色的大理石，伟大的，我们把红色的大理石扔到红色的桶里。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble, great, we dropped the
[SOUND] the red marble in the red bucket.
顺便说下，全球范围，那个标识符是指向一个新功能，所以
By the way, global scope, that identifier
is pointing at a new function, so
我们需要一个新的水桶
we need a new bucket.
让我们把它做个绿色
Let's make this one green.
全球范围说，当然，这里是你的绿色桶。
And the global scope says,
sure, here's your green bucket.
现在我们要和绿桶打交道了
Now we're gonna step into that function
and deal with the green bucket.
绿色桶，嘿范围问，我有正式的声明吗 ?
Hey green bucket, hey scope of ask,
I have a formal declaration for?
>> 扬声器 2: 问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Question.
>> 凯尔: 问题，听过吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Question, ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔: 但这里是你的 -- > 扬声器 2: 绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: But here's your-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green marble.
>> 凯尔: [SOUND] 绿色大理石就是绿色的桶。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: [SOUND] Green marble
goes the green bucket.
在该职能中不再有正式声明，我们将重返全球
No more formal declarations in that
function, we step back out to the global
在全球范围内，没有更正式的声明，我们也做了处理。
scope, no more formal declarations in the
global scope, and we're done processing.
现在它正在处理这个代码，让我们执行代码。
Now it's process this code,
let's execute the code.
记住所有范围的计划一切都已经完成了
Remember all the plans for all the scopes
and everything is already done,
我们已经没有任何装饰了我们只是有可执行的密码
we don't have any decoration anymore,
we just have executable code.
一个是要执行的，我们知道老师在什么岗位上 ?
Line one is going to execute, and we know
that teacher is in what kind of position?
老师的位置是什么 ?
What position is teacher in?
要么是源要么是
It's either a source or it's a?
>> 扬声器 2: 目标。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Target.
>> 凯尔: 目标，在此处的目标位置。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Target, and
it's in a target position here.
所以我们要说我们现在是执行引擎， VM，
So we're going to say we are now
the execution engine, the VM,
不管你想说什么
whatever you wanna call it.
我们将执行这一代码，我们将会说，嘿范围管理人员，
We are going to execute this code and
we are going to say, hey scope manager,
全球范围，我有老师的目标参考，听说过吗 ?
hey global scope, I have a target
reference for teacher, ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。 >> 凯尔: 是，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes,
因为范围内就有一个。
because there is one in the scope.
这里是你的 -- > 扬声器 3: 红色大理石。
So here’s your-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
>> 凯尔: 红色的大理石，非常感谢。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble, thank you very much.
我去右边我找到了价值
I go to the right hand side,
I find the value.
我把它分配给目标，我们用第 1 行做。
I assign it in the target,
and we are done with line 1.
现在行刑将转移到第 13 行因为记住
Now execution is gonna move to line 13,
because remember,
所有声明都被汇编了
all the declarations
have been compiled away.
我们还是在那里看到的是有象征意义的
We still see them there for
symbolic reasons, but
他们并不是这样做的，对，这只是一个可执行的代码。
they're not really there like that,
right, this is only executable code.
执行移至第 13 行。
So execution moves to line 13.
第 13 行本身如何执行?
How does line 13 itself execute?
全球范围，我有什么参考?
Hey, global scope,
I have a what kind of reference?
源。
Source.
>> 扬声器 2: 我有一个源引用。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I have a source reference.
> > 凯尔: 下面就在下面。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It's right down
here at the bottom.
我有一个资料来源
I have a source reference.
为什么是源参考?
Why is it a source reference?
>演讲者 4: 正在获得价值，对吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: It's getting values, right?
>> 凯尔: 最好的答案是它不是目标引用。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The best answer is because
it's not a target reference.
如果它没有接收目标，那么它必须是源， cuz 是唯一的两个选项。
If it's not receiving a target, it must be
a source, cuz that's the only two options.
所以我们清楚地看到它没有接收到目标
So we clearly see it's
not receiving a target,
它不是目标接收对象所以它必须是一个源
it's not the target receiving something,
so it must be a source.
那么，全球范围，我还有别的课源参考，
So, hey, global scope,
I have a source reference for other class,
每个人都听到了吗
every heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
>> 凯尔: 是的，这里是你的
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes, here is your.
>> 扬声器 2: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red marble.
>> 凯尔: 红色的大理石，我们去看红色大理石的东西，在概念上，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble, we go and look
what's in that red marble, conceptually,
那是什么记忆区
what's in that area of memory?
那红色的大理石现在装的是什么
What is that red marble holding right now?
>> 扬声器 2: 蓝色存储区。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Blue bucket.
>> 凯尔: 对这个函数的引用，我们称之为其他类，对吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: A reference to that function
which we call other class, right?
如果你愿意的话那是蓝色的水桶
It's the blue bucket if you will, exactly.
所以现在我们要执行这个
So now we're going to execute that,
这条线的末端是括号里的
which is what the parentheses
do on the end of that line.
他们执行我们发现的功能。
They execute the function that we found.
如果我们没有找到一个功能，我们就会得到一个什么样的错误，
If we hadn't found a function we would
have gotten a what kind of error,
有人记得吗
anybody remember?
类型错误，引用错误将不同。
A type error,
reference errors will be different.
我们只要一点点就好了好吗
We'll get to those in just a little bit,
okay?
好，我们正在执行其他类的功能。
All right, so
we are executing the other class function.
执行移至第 4 行。
Execution moves to line 4.
什么范围?
Hey, what scope?
>> 演讲者 2: 蓝色。 >> 凯尔: 蓝色范围，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Blue.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Blue scope,
其他类的范围。
hey scope of other class.
我有什么参考?
I have a what kind of reference?
>> 扬声器 2: 目标。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Target.
>> 凯尔: 我有目标引用吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: I have a target reference for?
>> 扬声器 2: 教师。 >> 凯尔: 听过，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Teacher.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Ever heard of it, and
答案是什么
the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
>凯尔 : 这是你的吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Here's your?
>> 扬声器 2: 蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Blue marble.
>> 凯尔: 蓝色大理石，伟大，现在我们有一个蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Blue marble, great,
so now we have a blue marble.
我们到右边。
We go to the right hand side.
我们找到了苏西的弦
We find the string Suzy.
我们把它分配给第 4 行
We assign it and we're done with line 4.
第五行我们有什么参考吗
Line 5, we have a what kinda reference?
>> 扬声器 2: 源。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: A source.
>> 凯尔: 源引用 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: A source reference for?
>> 扬声器 2: 全局作用域。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Global scope.
>> 演讲者 4: 控制台。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Console.
>> 凯尔: 控制台的源引用。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: A source reference for console.
你的范围呢
Hey scope of?
>> 扬声器 3: 蓝色存储区。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Blue bucket.
>> 凯尔: 其他类的范围。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Hey scope of other class.
你有没有听过控制台，答案是?
Have you ever heard of console,
and the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔: 否，那么下一步呢 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: No, so where do we go next?
>> 扬声器 2: 向上。 > > 凯尔: 我们上一级，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Up.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: We go up one level,
在这件案子里是全球性的
which in this case is the global.
我们问同一个问题，全球范围，我有一个源参考
And we ask the same question, hey global
scope, I have a source reference for
控制台，听说过它，答案是吗 ?
console, ever heard of it,
and the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。 >> 凯尔: 虽然我们没有申报，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Even though we didn't declare it,
JavaScript 环境已提供给我们。
the JavaScript environment
has provided it to us.
所以实际上就是在这个范围内，是不是在这个范围内，
So in effect it's there,
whether it's in the scope or not,
实际上是我们可以得到的
in effect it's available to us.
所以我们得到的回应是肯定的。
So the response that we get is yes.
这是你的红色大理石，也许是粉红色大理石。
Here's your red marble, essentially,
maybe it's a pink marble.
但这是你的红色大理石好吗
But here's your red marble, okay?
然后，我们可以访问一个方法，一个对象上的属性，等等。
And then we can access a method,
a property on the object, and so on and so
我们可以执行这个功能好吗
forth, and
we can execute the function, okay?
现在，执行已完成，第 13 行，我们移至第 14 行。
Now, execution's finished with line 13,
we move to line 14.
14 的执行完全如 13。
14 executes exactly like 13.
嘿全球范围我有什么参考
Hey, global scope I have
a what kind of reference?
>> 扬声器 2: 源引用。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Source reference.
>> 凯尔: 源引用 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Source reference for?
>> 演讲者 2: 应用程序。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Apps.
>> 凯尔: 听过它，答案是吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Ever heard of it and
the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。 >> 凯尔: 这是你的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Here's your.
>> 扬声器 2: 绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green marble.
>演讲者 3: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
>> 凯尔: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Red marble.
记住我们现在在全球范围内
Remember we're in the global scope now.
所以我们讨论的是这个范围内的一个标识，一个红色的大理石。
So we're talking about an identifier
in that scope, a red marble.
>> 演讲者 2: [LAUGH] >> 凯尔: 好的，好的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Okay, all right, so
现在我们有了红色大理石
now we have the red marble.
内存在那个位置有什么 ?
What's being held in
that location of memory?
>> 扬声器 4: 红色大理石表示绿色水桶。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Red marble
says go to green bucket.
>> 凯尔: 它是- >> 演讲者 4: 否?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It is-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: No?
>> 凯尔: 特定大理石正在引用具有以下功能的函数 :
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That particular marble is
referencing the function which has
与它相连的绿色范围。
the green scope attached to it.
但是这里是功能参考权吗 ?
But here's the function reference right?
函数有作用域，但它们不是作用域吗?
Functions have a scope but
they aren't a scope okay?
这是功能参考。
So here's the function reference.
我们按照你的意思来执行它
We execute it which is going to
end up invoking as you were saying
绿色的范围。
the green scope.
现在我们在绿色水桶里
So now we're in the green bucket.
我们将执行移至第 9 行。
We move execution to line 9.
第 9 行如何执行?
How does line 9 execute?
你的范围呢
Hey, scope of?
>> 扬声器 2: 绿色。 >> 凯尔: 绿桶，问的范围，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Green bucket, hey scope of ask,
什么样的参考
what kind of reference?
>> 扬声器 2: 目标引用。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Target reference.
>> 凯尔: 目标引用请求，是否已听过 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Target reference request,
ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。 >> 凯尔: 是的，这是你的吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes, here's your?
>> 扬声器 2: 绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green marble.
>> 凯尔: 绿色大理石，我们把 Y 放在右边
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Green marble, we take
the string Y on the right hand side,
请将其分配，现在已完成第 9 行。
assign it, and now line 9 is done.
最后，第 10 行，我们查找控制台。
Finally, line 10, we look up console.
我们在问的范围内找不到它，我们在哪里找到它呢 ?
We don't find it in the scope of ask,
where do we find it?
>> 演讲者 2: 在全球 [CROSSTALK] >> 凯尔:
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: In the global [CROSSTALK]
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So red marble, right,
我们在全球范围内找到它就像我们从第 5 行开始的那样
we find it in the global scope,
exactly like we did from line 5.
但是在我们可以在控制台上调用该日志方法之前，
But before we can call that log
method on the console object,
我们得先做些什么
what do we have to do first?
>> 演讲者 2: 你必须来源- >> 凯尔: 我们必须搞清楚
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You have to source-
&gt;&gt; Kyle: We've got to figure out what
就是。
that is.
那么这个问题会是，哎，范围呢 ?
So that question is going to be,
hey, scope of?
>> 扬声器 2: 绿色存储区。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green bucket.
>> 凯尔: 绿桶，问的范围，我有什么参考?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Green bucket, hey scope of ask,
I have a what kind of reference?
>> 扬声器 2: 源。 >> 凯尔: 源引用请求，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Source.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Source reference request,
听说过吗
ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 扬声器 2: 是。 >> 凯尔: 是的，这是你的吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes, here's your?
>> 扬声器 2: 绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Green marble.
>> 凯尔: 绿色大理石，当时的绿色大理石是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Green marble, and what is
in the green marble at that moment?
>> 扬声器 2: 为什么。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Why.
>> 凯尔: 这个字符串，为什么? 因为它是一个论点，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The string, Why?,
and because it's an argument,
我们该怎么做呢
what are we gonna do with that argument?
我们要把这一争论传递到那个功能上
We're going to pass that
argument into that function,
它具有将该参数指定给参数的效果。
which has the effect of assigning
that argument to a parameter.
所以最后的一步是我们没有看到它的功能但是
So the final step here,
which we don't see that function, but
最后的一步就是那个函数说，
the final step would have
been that function saying,
我有个接收任务的参数
hey I have a parameter that's
receiving this assignment.
我要查一下那个大理石，然后收到任务，每个人都有吗 ?
I need to look up that marble, then
receive the assignment, everybody with me?
同样的过程即使我们在那里看不到等号
Same process, even though we
don't see the equals sign there,
在概念上，同样的事情发生了，一个参数被分配给一个参数。
conceptually the same thing's happening,
an argument's assigned to a parameter.
好的，第 10 行，第 14 行了，我们的程序完成了。
Okay, line 10 is done, line 14 is done,
and our program is complete.